Federation of Ukrainian Student Organizations of America. Records, 1950-1966: A Finding Aid.
Records, 1950-1966.
Ukrainian Research Institute Library, Harvard University
HOLLIS 009838852
Federation of Ukrainian Student Organizations of America.
7 boxes (7 linear ft.)
Records of the Federation of Ukrainian Student Organizations of America. This collection forms one part of the Ukrainian Student Movement Archive.
Access is by appointment only. Contact the Institute Bibliographer/Archivist.
The Federation of Ukrainian Student Organizations of America (SUSTA) was founded in 1953 during the first congress of Ukrainian students in the United States, held at Columbia University. Eleonora Kulchytska was elected the federation's first president. She and subsequent presidents helped oversee and support the interests of the 654 members of SUSTA who were scattered throughout some fifty universities and colleges in the United States. The mission of the federation is to help foster and disseminate knowledge about Ukrainian history; to strengthen the moral and spiritual values of Ukrainian Americans, and to support and preserve Ukrainian culture and traditions; to prepare students to take part in the intellectual and practical life of the United States, or a free Ukraine; to coordinate the activities of member clubs and societies; and to raise money on behalf of students.
Organized in six series:
I. Congresses
II. Administration
III. Ukrainian student clubs
California
Colorado
Connecticut
Illinois
Indiana
Maryland
Massachusetts
Michigan
Minnesota
Nebraska
New Jersey
New York
Ohio
Pennsylvania
Washington DC
Wisconsin
IV. Member societies
V. Publications
A. SUSTA
B. Member clubs and societies
VI. Unprocessed materials
The records contain correspondence, minutes, resolutions, speeches, photographs, publications, and miscellaneous documents. This sub-collection of the Ukrainian Student Movement archive includes documents related to its founding congress held at Columbia University in 1953, as well as from subsequent congresses through the eighth held in Seton Hall University in 1966. The administrative files are comprised of circulars, letters, announcements, and other documents, with a number of files related to the publication of the organization's tenth anniversary book, Ukrains'ke studentstvo v Amerytsi (1963). The largest component of this collection includes material from the nearly 50 student associations and clubs at various American universities and colleges, with the most active of these being affiliated with academic communities in Chicago, Baltimore, New York City, Cleveland, and Philadelphia. There is also a significant amount of material documenting the activities of the Zarevo Ukrainian Student Association, which holds a special status in the federation. The records include a number of newsletters published by these Ukrainian student associations, as well as by the administration of the federation.
For other collections comprising the Ukrainian Student Movement Archive see:
Records of the Central Union of Ukrainian Students (TseSUS)
Records of the Union of Ukrainian Student Associations in Germany (SUSON)
- I. Congresses ([Box 1])
  - Conference of Ukrainian student organizations in America (15-16 Nov. 1952, Cleveland)--greetings, 1952
  - 1st Congress (10-12 Apr. 1953, Columbia University)--correspondence, 1952-1953
  - 1st Congress (10-12 Apr. 1953, Columbia University)--by-laws and minutes, 1953
  - 1st Congress (10-12 Apr. 1953, Columbia University)--list of attendees, 1953
  - Congress (8 May 1954, Chicago), 1954
  - 2nd Congress (11-12 June 1955, Columbia University)--resolutions, 1955
  - 3rd-4th Congresses (16-17 June 1957, Cleveland: 3-5 July 1959, Philadelphia; inc. photographs of delegates at the 3rd Congress), 1956-1959
  - 4th-5th Congresses (3-5 July 1959, Philadelphia; 1-2 July 1961,Wayne State University), 1956-1961
  - 5th Congress (1-2 July 1961, Wayne State University)--photographs, 1961
    - Congressional ball (Detroit), July 1, 1961
    - Delegates and Executive Board, 1961
    - Executive Board, 1961
    - Pochtar, Mykhailo, 1961
    - Presidential address--Sawchuk, Konstantyn, July 1, 1961
    - Prybyla, Walter (newly elected president), 1961
    - Session, 1961
  - Ukrainian National Anthem, 1961
  - Ukrainian Studies Chair Fund address--Chemych, Stepan, 1961
  - All-Student Jubilee Congress (16-17 May 1959, Baltimore)--Preparatory Committee, 1959
  - All-Student Jubilee Congress (16-17 May 1959, Baltimore)--greetings, 1959
  - All-Student Jubilee Congress (16-17 May 1959, Baltimore)--speeches, 1959
  - All-Student Jubilee Congress (16-17 May 1959, Baltimore)--photographs, 1959
    - Emblem, n.d.
    - Krawciw, Bohdan with Vol. Bakum, Kostiantyn Savchuk, Osyp Zinkevych, and Oksana Pisetska, 1959
    - 6th Congress (6-7 June 1963, Western Reserve University), 1963
    - 6th Congress (6-7 June 1963, Western Reserve University), 1963
    - 7th Congress (10-11 July 1965, Drexel Institute of Technology), 1965
    - 8th Congress (25-26 June 1966, Seton Hall University), 1966
- II. Administration ([Boxes 1, 2, 3])
  - Clippings, 1950-1956 ([Box 1])
  - Misc., 1950-1962 ([Box 1])
  - Register of correspondence (sent), 1952-1953 ([Box 1])
  - Circulars, 1952, 1954 ([Box 1])
  - Speeches, 1953 ([Box 1])
  - Misc., 1953 ([Box 1])
  - Executive--correspondence, 1953-1954 ([Box 1])
  - Executive--correspondence, 1953-1954 ([Box 1])
  - Ukrainian Congress Committee of America--survey on Ukrainian studies in American colleges, 1953-1954 ([Box 1])
  - Executive--minutes, 1953-1955 ([Box 1])
  - Scholarship fund, 1953-1955 ([Box 1])
  - Correspondence with Ukrainian student organizations, 1953-1957 ([Box 1])
  - Clippings, 1953-1961 ([Box 1])
  - Correspondece with the Ukrainian Canadian Students' Union, 1954 ([Box 1])
  - Onuferko, Teodosii--Correspondence, 1954 ([Box 1])
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1954-1955 ([Box 1])
  - Misc., 1954-1956 ([Box 1])
  - Conferences--clippings, 1954-1960 ([Box 1])
  - President--correspondence (rec.), 1954-1962 ([Box 1])
  - Correspondence with TseSUS, 1955-1956 ([Box 1])
  - Correspondence with the Ukrainian Congress Committee of America, 1955-1956 ([Box 1])
  - Misc., 1955-1961 ([Box 1])
  - Misc., 1955-1963 ([Box 1])
  - Misc., 1955-1967 ([Box 1])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--Administration--photographs, 1956-1963 ([Box 1])
    - Conference of Ukrainian Student Organizations in America (15-16 Nov. 1962, Cleveland)--TseSUS, American Division and UAS in Chicago), 1962
    - Dorozhynskyi, Pavlo, n.d.
    - Executive Board, n.d.
    - Fedyshyn, Oleh, n.d.
    - First Higher Education Conference (21-23 Sep. 1956, Soiuzivka)--Halychyn, Dmytro with delegates, 1956
    - Fourth Higher Education Conference (26-27 Sep. 1959, Soiuzivka)--Delegates, 1959
    - Fourth Higher Education Conference (26-27 Sep. 1959, Soiuzivka)--Halychyn, Dmytro and Orysia Machuk, 1959
    - Huta, Ivan, n.d.
    - Melnyk, Zinovii--Head of the Working Committee, SUSTA, n.d.
    - Petryshyn, Volodymyr--Vice President of SUSTA, 1955-1957, n.d.
    - Savchuk, Kostiantyn, n.d.
    - Second Secondary Education Conference (9 Feb. 1963, Troy, NY), 1963
    - Stercho, Petro--President of TseSUS, American Division, n.d.
    - Third Higher Education Conference (19-21 Sep. 1958, Soiuzivka)--Participants, 1958
    - Third Organizational Conference (1958, Newark, NJ)--Participants, 1958
    - Tomorug, Myroslava, 1958
    - Ukrainian Studies Fund--Chemych, Stepan, n.d.
  - 10th Anniversary Book--Administration--photographs, 1956-1963 ([Box 1])
    - Ukrainian Studies Fund--Chemych, Stepan with his wife Mariia and Larysa Hanushchak at the 5th Congress ((1-2 July 1961, Wayne State University), July 1, 1961
    - Ukrainian Studies Fund--Fundraising poster, n.d.
    - United States National Student Association and the Executive Board of SUSTA--Meeting (2 Dec. 1961, Philadelphia), Dec. 2, 1961
    - Vasylkivska, Zhenia, n.d.
    - Vynnytskyi, Zenon R., n.d.
    - Unidentified (two women in Ukrainian folk costumes), n.d.
  - Misc., 1956-1966 ([Box 1])
  - Programs and announcements, 1957-1961 ([Box 1])
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 ([Box 2])
  - Executive--correspondence, 1958-1960 ([Box 2])
  - Ukrainian Canadian Students' Union--announcements, 1958-1960 ([Box 2])
  - Ukrainian Student Fund, 1958-1963 ([Box 2])
  - Circulars, 1958-1964 ([Box 2])
  - Information Service of the Ukrainian Canadian Students' Union--circulars, 1959-1960 ([Box 2])
  - Executive--minutes, 1959-1960 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--photographs (copies), 1959-1962
    - Misc., 1960 ([Box 2])
    - Official register, 1960-1961
    - 10th Anniversary Book--12th Annual Colgate Conference on American Foreign Policy (10-14 July 1961, Hamilton, NY)--photographs:, July 1961
    - Delegates (inc. W. Prybyla, V. Dushnyck, L. Ortynskyj, and S. Jarema), July 1961
    - Delegates with Senator Jacob Javitts (inc. J. Prybyla, D. Horodeckyj, M. Prybyla, Mrs. Everett Case, and Walter Prybyla, July 1961
    - Harland, Cleveland, Walter D. Prybyla, and Everett Case, July 1961
  - 10th Anniversary Book--First Vacation Days (5-6 Aug. 1961, Cleveland)--photographs: ([Box 2])
    - Participants, Aug. 1961
    - Radio program with newly elected SUSTA executives, Aug. 1961
  - Correspondence, minutes and circulars, 1961-1962 ([Box 2])
  - Misc., 1961-1962 ([Box 2])
  - Executive--minutes, 1961-1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--international activity--photographs:, 1961-1963 ([Box 2])
    - 14th Annual National Student Congress (20-30 Aug. 1961, Madison, WI)--Retting, Richard and Bohdan Futei, with other delegates, Aug. 1961
    - 14th Annual National Student Congress (20-30 Aug. 1961, Madison, WI)--Retting, Richard raising a toast to delegates, Aug. 1961
    - 14th Annual National Student Congress (20-30 Aug. 1961, Madison, WI)--Ukrainian exhibit, Aug. 1961
    - 14th Annual National Student Congress (20-30 Aug. 1961, Madison, WI)--United Nations Students' General Assembly, Aug. 1961
    - 15th Annual National Student Congress (Columbus, OH), 1962
    - 15th Annual National Student Congress (Columbus, OH)--Kupchyk, Liuba and Liubomyr Zobniv, 1962
    - 15th Annual National Student Congress (Columbus, OH)--Matytskiv, Tania and Liubomyr Zobniv, 1962
    - United Nations Students' General Assembly--Voice of Free Ukraine (Ukraine secedes from the Soviet Union) (New York), Mar. 23-24, 1962
    - Visit to the U. S. State Department (Washington DC), Apr. 19-20, 1963
    - Visit to the U. S. State Department (Washington DC), Apr. 19-20, 1963
    - Visit to the U. S. State Department (Washington DC), Apr. 19-20, 1963
    - Visit to Voice of America (Washington DC), Apr. 19-20, 1963
    - Visit with Rev. Harris, Chaplain to the U.S. Senate (Washington DC), Apr. 19-20, 1963
    - Visit to Washington DC, Apr. 19-20, 1963
    - Visit to Washington DC, Apr. 19-20, 1963
  - Academic Commission, 1962 ([Box 2])
  - Misc., 1962 ([Box 2])
  - Reports (administrative and departmental), 1962-1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--history of SUSTA, 1962-1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--correspondence and project plan, 1962-1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--correspondence, 1962-1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--correspondence, 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--orders, 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--correspondence (sent), 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--proofs, 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--Publication Committee--photographs, 1963 ([Box 2])
    - Publication Committee at work (Baltimore), May 4, 1963
    - Kupchyk, Liuba, n.d.
  - 10th Anniversary Book--manuscripts, 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--Conference of Ukrainian student organizations in America (DiSek-u), 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--Ukrainian Student Archive-Museum, 1963 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--Former and inactive student clubs, 1963 ([Box 2])
  - Misc., 1963-1964 ([Box 2])
  - 10th Anniversary Book--misc., n.d. ([Box 2])
  - Ukrainian Student Days--speeches, n.d. ([Box 2])
  - Ukrainian Student Days--speeches, n.d. ([Box 2])
  - World University Service--misc. publications, n.d. ([Box 3])
  - Misc., n.d. ([Box 3])
- III. Ukrainian Student Clubs ([Boxes 3, 4, 5])
  - California ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian-American Student Club (USC) at University of California, Berkeley, 1953-1954
    - USC at UC, Berkeley, 1953-1960
  - Colorado ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian Student Club at University of Colorado, Boulder, n.d. (inc. photograph of Ania Wynar, 1961)
  - Connecticut ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian Student Club in Connecticut, 1953-1955
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in Hartford--photographs, 1953, 1961-1963
      - Bandera, Iaroslav, n.d.
      - Bandera, Volodymyr, n.d.
      - Boichuk, Stepan, n.d.
      - Chaikovskyi, Stepan, n.d.
      - Government (M. Krupa, I. Zakhariasevych, and U. Skochdopol), 1962-1963
      - Krasii, Myron, n.d.
      - Luchkan, Iaroslav, n.d.
      - Meeting in commemoration of Battle of Kruty, Feb. 15, 1963
      - Members at a meeting, 1953
      - Zakhariasevych, Ihor, n.d.
    - USC in Hartford, 1963
  - Illinois ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian Academic Society (UAS) in Chicago--minutes, 1950-1953
    - UAS in Chicago, 1951-1957
    - UAS in Chicago--register of correspondence, 1952-1958
    - UAS in Chicago--list of members present at meetings, 1953-1959
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in Chicago--correspondence (rec.), 1950-1951
    - USC in Chicago--correspondence (rec.), 1953-1954
    - USC in Chicago--reports, 1953-1959
    - USC in Chicago--correspondence (sent), 1953-1962
    - USC in Chicago--correspondence (rec.), 1953-1962
    - USC in Chicago--correspondence (rec.), 1956-1959
    - USC in Chicago, 1962-1963
    - USC in Chicago--photographs:
      - Dubytskyi, Iurii, Tania Matiitsiv, Bohdan Satsiuk, Iurii Gaietskyi, Larysa Matiitsiv, Ihor Pryima, and Bohdan Bodnaruk, 1963
      - Gaietskyi, Iurii, Tania Matiitsiv, Bohdan Bodnaruk, Ihor Pryima, and Iurii Dubytskyi, 1963
      - Matiitsiv, Tania, 1963
      - Piletskyi, Dmytro, n.d.
      - Piletskyi, Dmytro with student representatives from Holland, Japan, the United States, Scotland, and Iceland, 1954
      - Stercho, P., Vasyl Nahirniak, Volodymyr Tymtsiurak, Mykola Dymashevskyi, Mykola Iashko, and Pylyp Maksymonko, 1950
      - Unidentified, n.d.
    - Ukrainian Student Organization (USO) at University of Illinois, Urbana--photographs:, 1962
      - Brytsky, Mykola, n.d.
      - Brytsky, Mykola--painting Way of Life, n.d.
      - Members, n.d.
      - Ukrainian exhibit, 1962
    - USO at University of Illinois, Urbana, 1963
  - Indiana ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian Student Club at Indiana University, Bloomington, 1963
  - Maryland ([Boxes 3, 4])
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in Baltimore, 1955-1963 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--10th Anniversary Book--photographs:, 1955-1963
      - All Nations' Day, 1958 ([Box 3])
      - Andriivskyi Vechir, Dec. 1955
      - Bandurist Levytskyi with members (Saint Agnes College), n.d.
      - Battle of Kruty commemoration, Jan. 1957
      - Bendiuk, Mariika, Liuba Kupchyk, Nadia Bendiuk and Oles Lomatskyi, 1961
      - Dance and choral group, n.d.
      - Hanas, Orest, n.d.
      - Iurchyshyn, Bohdan, n.d.
      - Kharkhalis, Taras, n.d.
      - Kotyk, Iurii, 1955
      - Members, 1963
      - Picnic, May 1960
      - Pisetska-Vynnytska, Oksana, n.d.
      - Polishchuk, Orest, n.d.
      - Pylypchuk, Mykhailo, n.d.
      - Shaviak, Iaroslav, n.d.
      - Student Days, 1957
      - Student Days, 1958
      - Student Days, 1959
      - Ukrainian Student Day (in commemoration of Battle of Kruty)--Baltimore Mayor Harold Grady with students, Jan. 1961
      - Unidentified
    - USC in Baltimore--invitations, 1956-1959 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--notices, 1956-1959 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Student Days--correspondence (Organizing Committee) 1957 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--cash book, 1957-1958 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Mount Saint Agnes College, 1957-1959 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Osyp Zinkevych--correspondence, 1957-1959 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore, 1957-1960 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore, 1957-1964 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore, 1957-1966 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Student Days--correspondence (Organizing Committee) 1958 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Student Days--greetings, 1958 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--cash book, 1958 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Relief Department--People to People Program, 1958 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Relief Department, 1958-1959 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore, 1958-1960 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--minutes, 1958-1961 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore, 1958-1962 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore, 1958-1963 ([Box 3])
    - USC in Baltimore--Student Days, 1960-1963 ([Box 3])
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) at University of Maryland, College Park, 1960-1961 ([Box 4])
    - USC at University of Maryland, College Park--photographs:
      - Members, n.d. ([Box 4])
      - Palijczuk, Wasyl, n.d.
      - Palijczuk, Wasyl--paintings and sculptures, c. 1961-1963
      - Ukraine exhibit, 1959
      - Ukraine exhibit, n.d.
    - USC at University of Maryland, College Park--photographs: ([Box 4])
      - Ukrainian intramural volleyball team (T. Prytula, J. Korz, J. Zarubaiko, A. Traska, S. Eringis, D. Kupchyk, V. Drazdys, and W. Kurinij), n.d.
      - Ukrainian members of the University of Maryland soccer team (W. Kurinij, J. Zarubaiko, D. Kupchyk, N. Limar, and J. Korz), n.d.
      - Ukrainian Students Dance Group, n.d.
  - Massachusetts ([Box 4])
    - Ukrainian-American Student Circle in Boston, 1953-1954
      (inc. photograph of members: O. Shudliuk, N. Volianyk-Deichakivska, T. Novosivskyi, and R. Napurko), 1954
    - Ukrainian Student Club in Boston, 1963
  - Michigan ([Box 4])
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) at University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1953-1954
    - USC at University of Michigan, Ann Arbor--photographs:
      - Bilaniuk, Oleksa (Baltimore), 1958
      - Christmas Eve, 1953
      - Christmas Eve, 1962
      - Cisaruk, Yarema, Tania Mikiczenko, and Victor Halycz, n.d.
      - International Festival--Ukraine exhibit, 1962
      - International Festival--Ukrainian Students Dance Group, n.d.
      - Members, Spring 1952
      - Nehrebetskyi, Iurii, n.d.
      - Party, n.d.
      - Ukraine exhibit, May 1952
      - Ukrainian radio program (O. Bilaniuk, Z. Melnyk, and S. Biletskyi), Dec. 18, 1952
    - USC at University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1963
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) at Wayne State University, Detroit, 1953-1954
    - USC at Wayne State University, Detroit, 1960-1963 (inc. photograph of administration, Feb. 1963)
  - Minnesota ([Box 4])
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) at University of Minnesota, Minneapolis,1953-1954
    - USC at University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, 1963
  - Nebraska ([Box 4])
    - Ukrainian Student Club in Lincoln, 1953-1954
  - New Jersey ([Box 4])
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in Newark, 1953-1954
    - USC in Newark, 1963 (inc. photographs of members, n.d.)
    - Ukrainian Student Circle at Rutgers University, Newark, 1963 (inc. photographs of members--A. Koval, M. Onyshkevych, N. Khytra, O. Buk, N. Kachmar, and Z. Benke--1963)
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in Trenton--photographs:, 1956-1963
      - Haftkevych, Ivan, c. 1962-1963
      - Members, 1957-1959
      - Members, 1958
      - Members, 1959
      - Members (Longwood Gardens, DL), 1961
      - Mykytyn, I. Iu., n.d.
      - Sich, Dmytro, 1958
      - Ukrainian exhibit (Trenton Junior College), 1956
      - Ukrainian exhibit (Trenton Junior College)-- Myroslava Hlushok and Mariia Mrochko, 1956
    - USC in Trenton, 1963
  - New York ([Box 4])
    - Ukrainian Student Society (USS) in Buffalo, 1953-1954
    - USS in Buffalo, 1960-1963
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in New York--10th Ann. Bk.--photographs, 1948-1963
      - Baranetskyi, Volodymyr, n.d.
      - Battle of Kruty commemoration, n.d.
      - Choir (New Haven), Apr. 24, 1948
      - Coordinating Committee of Youth Organizations in New York, 1958
      - Delegates to the 4th Congress of SUSTA (A. Kipa, O. Matushevska, V. Bakum, and P. Dorozhynskyi) (Philadelphia), n.d.
      - Dorozhynskyi, Pavlo, c. 1962
      - "Dumka" choir (Ia. Bachynskyi, T. Rabii, M. Zhovnir, L. Pobihushka, S. Iavdoshyn, B. Hlynskyi, B. Bakum, and O. Matushevska), 1959
      - Government, 1960-1963
      - Higher Education Conference, Feb. 24, 1951
      - Kipa, Albert, 1962
      - Kotliarchuk, Ihor, n.d.
      - Meeting, 1956
      - Members at SUSTA Conference (P. Dorozhynskyi, O. Matushevska, M. Chemych, A. Procyk, Iu. Wynar, K. Savchuk, V. Shevchuk, and B. Bakum) (Seton Hall University), June 1960
      - Shevchenko, Oleksii, Dec. 1956
      - Ukrainian Youth Festival, 1957
      - Zarevo, 1959-1960
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) in New York--10th Ann. Bk.--photographs, 1948-1963
      - Unidentified, n.d.
    - USC in New York, 1952-1953
    - USC in New York, 1953-1954
    - USC in New York, 1953-1958
    - USC in New York--correspondence, 1954-1956
    - USC in New York--minutes, 1954, 1957
    - USC in New York, 1954-1958
    - USC in New York--correspondence (rec.), 1955-1956
    - USC in New York--correspondence, 1956-1957
    - USC in New York, 1957-1958
    - USC in New York, 1959-1960, 1962
    - USC in New York, 1963
    - Ukrainian Student Club (USC) at City College, New York, 1953-1954
    - USC at City College, New York--photographs, 1954-1962
      - Lashchyk, Ievhen, n.d.
      - Members, c. 1954-1955
      - Members, c. 1954-1955
      - Members, Spring 1957
      - Members, 1958
      - Members, 1959
      - Members, 1962
      - Members, n.d.
      - Shuhan, Iurii, n.d.
      - Smulka, Oksana, n.d.
      - Ukrainian exhibit, 1955
      - Ukrainian fair (Kh. Zharska, M. Salyk-Iatsushko, L. Tkachuk-Hoshko, and I. Havryliuk), 1956
    - USC at City College, New York, 1963
    - Ukrainian Student Circle (USC) at Columbia University, New York, 1953-1954
    - USC at Columbia University, New York--photographs, 1956-1961
      - Armstrong, John--Lecture, Apr. 11, 1957
      - Bissonnette, George--Lecture, May 10, 1957
      - Chemych, Stepan, n.d.
      - Christmas meeting, Jan. 8, 1958
      - Shevelov, George, n.d.
      - Surmach, Iaroslav--Lecture, Nov. 15, 1956
      - Taras Shevchenko exhibit, 1961
    - Ukrainian Student Circle at Fordham University, New York--photographs, 1966
      - Laba, Roman, 1966
      - Voloshyn, Iurii, n.d.
    - Ukrainian Student Circle (USC) at Hunter College, New York, 1953-1954
    - USC at Hunter College, New York, 1963 (inc. photographs of Kovaliuk, Jeanette, n.d.; Ukrainian exhibit (L. Abramiuk, V. Lashchyk, Kh. Konashevych, I. Chornodolska, and A. Neprel) 1961)
    - Ukrainian Student Club at New York University, New York, 1954 (inc. photographs of International Festival--Ukrainian exhibit, 1962; Members, 1963; Venger-Tsikalo, Ievheniia, n.d.)
    - Ukrainian Student Club in Rochester, 1963 (inc. photograph of members, Mar. 1963)
    - Luka Myshuha Ukrainian Student Club (USC) at Syracuse University, 1958-1960
    - USC at Syracuse University--photographs, 1958-1960
      - Christmas Formal Dance Party, Dec. 27, 1958
      - Freedom Manifestation, Sep. 19, 1959
      - Golden Anniversary White House Conference on Children and Youth (Washington, DC), Apr. 1960
      - International Brotherhood Week, Feb. 21-26, 1960
      - Socialite Dance Club meeting--Ukrainian Sword Dance, Feb. 1960
      - Ukrainian Students Day--Syracuse Mayor Anthony A. Henninger with students and other Ukrainian community representatives, Jan. 1960
    - Ukrainian-American Student Society (UASS) at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, 1961-1963
    - UASS at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy--photographs:, 1962-1963